Albert Tonderai Chinyani

Full Stack Engineer |Test Automation engineer| Quality Assurance Engineer | chinyanialbert@gmail.com | +263777148679

Address: 4 Danbury Malboureign, Harare, Zimbabwe

LinkedIn: Albert Chinyani | DOB: 07/12/1995

PROFILE

A passionate and versatile technocrat with work experience in Software Development and Quality assurance, research and analysis in huge projects. Possess strong problem-solving driven software development skills focusing on mobile, web as well as systems development.

EDUCATION

BINDURA UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE EDUCATION, Zimbabwe

BSc Computer Science – Distinction

August 2015 – June

2019

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

-CERTIFIED SOPHOS WEB APPLIANCE V4.2 -ENGINEER (2020 -

- AWS Partner: Cloud Economics Accreditation - AWS Partner: Cloud Technical Accreditation

- ISTQB Fundamentals – Pending 2022

DEVELOPMENT EXPERTISE

Languages: Java, C#, Python, JavaScript.

DBMS: Oracle DBMS, Microsoft SQL, MySQL, SQLite,

PostgreSQL.

DevOps: Git, Jenkins, AWS, Google Cloud, Docker, Jira,

Maven, Ant.

Testing tools: Selenium, Appium, TestNG, RestAssured,

Cucumber, Postman.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WAER Systems - Quality Assurance Engineer Lancing, United Kingdom (Remote) April 2020-Present

- Reviewing quality specifications and technical design documents to provide timely and meaningful feedback
- Creating detailed, comprehensive and well-structured test plans and test cases for Back-End APIs and Front-End UI
- Estimating, prioritizing, planning and coordinating quality testing activities
- Following up on bug reports brought up by customers to validate the issue and suggest solutions
- Identifying and selecting the automation test cases
- Applying various designs and documenting the automation test strategy
- Creating an automation test plan and getting approval
- Configuring Selenium and Appium Test Environments
- Writing Automation test scripts in Java
- Creating, enhancing, debugging, and running the test cases
- Performing Mobile tests across different devices and operating systems.
- Creating test reports so that there is confidence in the quality of the product developed
- Designing Jenkins Pipeline for running the Tests
- Collating and monitoring the defect management process
- Managing the changes and executing regression tests
- Coming up with exact solutions for problems related to object identity and error handling
- Interacting with customers/clients to solve the various issues they face and updating on the situation

Sagehill Business Solutions- Software Engineer Harare, Zimbabwe May 2019 – March 2020

- Meeting and liaising with clients to establish their initial requirements and initial specification document
- Social media marketing, search engine optimization, website design management and graphic design
- Created workflows, approval processes and validation guidelines based on internal stakeholder needs.
- Lead developer accounting Software for management of accounting services
- Collected, evaluated, developed, documented, communicated requirements and supported user testing.
- Developed, documented and revised system design procedures, testing protocols and quality standards.
- Gathered requirements through interviews, document analysis, requirements workshops, site visits, use cases, business process descriptions and workflow analysis.
- Designing overall architecture of the web, mobile or desktop application
- Maintain quality and ensure responsiveness of applications.
- Collaborating with the rest of the engineering team to design and launch new features.
- Maintain code integrity and organization.
- Working with graphic designers and converting designs to visual elements.
- Understanding and implementation of security and data protection. Designing, implementing monitoring and training in cyber security solutions. (Sophos)
- Highly experienced with back-end programming languages (PHP,Java,.Net)
- Development experience for both mobile and desktop.
- Developed and consumed several APIs (such-as REST-API, SOAP).

• Worked with code versioning tools (Git, Mercurial or SVN)

Bindura University of Science Education – Research assistant (software dev) Zimbabwe January 2019 – August 2019

- Identified and compiled lists of potential research subjects in accordance current problems that are being faced in Zimbabwe
- Developed, documented and revised, concepts, system design procedures, testing protocols and quality standards.
- Gathered requirements through interviews, document analysis, requirements workshops, site visits, use cases, business process descriptions and workflow analysis.
- Development of multi-platform software, mobile application desktop application hybrid systems,IOT, artificial intelligence simulations.
- Presented the proof of concepts to several stackholders including the research board at Bindura university clients and potential investors
- Published research documents on the innovations and problem-solving concepts
- Developed a fibre and copper real-time theft, interruption, or damage detection and alert system pin-pointing the faulty location. (Concept). Developed a tobacco grading system for TIMB Zimbabwe for the tobacco floors (concept)

REFERENCES

- Projects Manager Sagehill Business Solutions
- Mr J Tseriwa
- Mobile: +263 773289802

Email: jtseriwa@sagehilltechnologies.com

- Lead Tester Waer Systems
- Ms C. Matema
- Mobile: +263775495677
- Email: <u>cmatema@waersystems.info</u>
- Chairperson Computer Science Department Bindura University of Science Education (BUSE)
- DR LC Sakala
- Mobile: +263713 644 733
 Email: lsakala@buse.ac.zw